AIDABA: So you have marks for me?
ALOY: What do you mean?
From the Hunting Grounds.
Oh, right. You're new here.
What do you want with my marks?
You hunters and your badges.
I'm not gonna take them.
What do I do with these marks?
If you earn marks in all three trials
at each of the five Hunting Grounds, come to me.
I can give you up to three weapons.
One for fifteen Half Suns,
one for fifteen Full Suns,
and one you'll love for all Blazing Suns!
I need a few more.
Okay.
Once you get marks from the trials at every Hunting Ground,
come back and we'll see what I can give you.
Aren't you a little out of your way, Nora?
Your Sacred Lands don't extend this far.
I go where I like.
What do you do here?
I'm the keeper of these hunting grounds.
Which means, of course, that I'm the local representative of the Hunters Lodge.
I oversee the leverage trials here.
Not that a vagabond Nora has any chance of passing them.
You might be surprised.
I doubt it.
So how'd you wind up here?
I didn't "wind up" here, it's an honour.
I don't expect you to get it, but I'm
well regarded at the Hunters Lodge back in Meridian.
So much so they sent you out here to pitch your tent in the wilds?
Are you going to take part in a trial or stand here prattling at me?
Tell me about the trials.
These hunting grounds offer the leverage trials.
They focus on gaining an edge by leveraging machines against each other.
You might, for instance, take a weapon from one machine and use it on another.
It's hard, but the firepower is often worth the risk.
Let me know which trail you're interested in.
For this trial you must use the cannon on a Ravager's back
to take down other machines.
KEEPER: And so it's time to begin.
Heavy, it's hard too.
Needed that.
Back to your business.
I can't believe it.
You've earned a Blazing Sun on the first try.
I know who you are, girl.
The Nora who can control machines.
So I've got a trial just for you.
Use your spear to take control of two Ravagers.
Get them to help you take down a Thunderjaw.
Good hit!
I think I'm in the clear.
I can't believe it.
You've earned a Blazing Sun on the first try.
For this trial, you must use the Thunderjaw's cannon to destroy Ravagers.
KEEPER: Get out there and give it your best.
I've almost got you!
Now they're hunting me.
I can't believe it.
You've earned a Blazing Sun on the first try.
I'll be going now.
Uh-huh.
Glinthawks, they're never giving up scrap.
Aah.
I'll find a use for you.
Mmm, I waited for you.
Time passing pulls the anticipation tight as wire.
Ah, how many has it been now?
I don't keep count, Nil.
Don't keep count? Sometimes I just don't get you.
Are you like us or a little different?
Hopefully a little different.
That's what you're gonna tell yourself.
Shall we get started?
Full already.
Can't be too prepared.
BANDIT: Saw a herd of Shell-Walkers and thought it was my lucky day.
ALOY: That's an alarm. Would make enough noise to bring in more.
ALOY: That puts it out of action.
BANDIT: Get her!
BANDIT: Who knows where she is?
BANDIT: …got trouble, light the signal!
BANDIT: Die, die!
BANDIT: I missed! You're dead, dead!
ALOY: Hello!
ALOY: The bandit's captives.
BANDIT: Fight!
CARJA: Just because he failed to kill the Sun-King
doesn't mean he's any less guilty, he should pay!
CARJA: So there are Oseram in the Sundom now.
I get up, I work, same as always.
CARJA: Ugh, egg for breakfast and it's not sitting well with me.
CARJA: The Oseram have gone too far
this time, Dervahl should die for his crimes.
CARJA: We owe you for defending the Sun-King.
ALOY: Forget about travelling light.
CARJA: If I got my hands on Dervahl…
CARJA: What reason do Oseram need for anything that they do?
CARJA: That crazy Oseram … 'til the machine rider stopped him.
CARJA: Didn't even hesistate. She stood between the assassin and our Sun-King.
These little moments are refreshing, aren't they?
That could be the least creepy thing you've said to me.
Aah, that glimpse of yourself in their eyes,
just as the cloud of death passes across them.
Never mind, there it goes.
Ambushes, raiding parties, even corrupted machines!
The mortal wounds just open themselves to accept my arrows.
But you knew this already.
You've been walking on the edge of life and death.
I can tell.
Yeah, it's a long story.
With many quick endings, I hope.
You know, Nil, if you get tired of bandits, there is a group called "The Eclipse".
That's a political situation.
They're murderers, and they're raising an army of machines,
that's a little more than politics.
Don't hate me for being single-minded.
Besides, I wouldn't bet on how long the Shadow Carja
are gonna last if you're in for the kill.
Makes you wish you could kill them more than once doesn't it?
No, once is enough.
You're right, of course, once is enough when you really make it count.
What's the matter? You look disappointed.
Oh, the bandit clans have gone.
I hear another turned back at the southern plains
just at a sniff of the legend we carved.
That's what all this bloodshed was for, to end the bandit threat.
But now there is nothing left to kill … unless? No, no.
I guess this is our last farewell.
After all we've been through this isn't the place for that.
There's a mesa south of Meridian with a view of the Spearshafts.
Meet me there.
Stocking up! [whistle]
I've been seen!
It'd be fascinating if they weren't looking for me.
Gotta follow up!
Uh-oh!
Safe, for a few minutes anyway.
What is this place?
Sssh!
Er, what are you doing?
I was listening to the herd.
Have you come for the stealth trials?
I'm not sure.
You must decide.
Who are you?
I am the keeper of these grounds.
So how did you come to be here?
I was once, like many members of the Lodge, manoeuvring, hunting for status.
But my impatience hampered the true hunt.
Are you a member?
No, I am only a Fledgling.
I prefer the music of the wild over the cacophony of squawking birds.
I didn't know that, of course, until I came here.
It forced me to listen, to breathe.
And finally to master the art of stealth.
Don't you ever miss, you know, talking?
Not at the moment, no.
What are the trials?
I offer the stealth trials.
Some believe charging in with a mighty weapon makes them a hunter.
But it's a good way to fall under the hooves of a stampede.
A true hunter chooses the approach that best suits the kill.
Mastering stealth may well save your life.
Have you decided which trial you'll take?
Choose and I can give you the details.
The Watchers of the herd attack quickly.
Take them down while in stealth to prove your skill.
KEEPER: I start timing once you slide down a rope.
No need to draw attention.
Can't have you giving away the hunt.
I can get out of this.
Such skill from an outlander on your first attempt.
Take this Blazing Sun as your proof.
Shell-Walkers guard their cargo with their lives.
In this trial, you must loot four of their containers in the allotted time.
KEEPER: Let the trial begin.
I think I'm in the clear.
Such skill from an outlander on your first attempt.
Take this Blazing Sun as your proof.
Stalkers have defeated many hunters who favour brute force over patience.
Don't make that mistake.
If you're up to the task, defeat these Stalkers
and you'll receive the mark you deserve.
KEEPER: Slide down a rope to start.
Low and quiet does it.
Such skill from an outlander on your first attempt.
Take this Blazing Sun as your proof.
With so many Suns you may wish to speak to Aidaba in Meridian.
She will have special gear for you.